Guide to the Anne Loftis Papers, 1953-1978
Department of Special Collections
- UNIONS
  - IWW (Industrial Workers of the World): notes for We Shall Be All, a history of the IWW by Melvin Dubofsky; The Industrial Union in Agriculture, by Tom Connors; Arizona Labor Journal for 1917(xerox); xeroxed pages from So Shall Ye Reap, the story of Cesar Chavez and the farm workers movement by Joan London and Henry Anerson; xeroxed pages from The Wobblies, by Patrick Renshaw; notes from A History of American Labor, by Joseph Raybock; The California Casual and His Revolt, by Carlton Parker; Tales of the IWW, by Paul Shinoff; Songs for Rebel Workers; The Story of the Ford Case, by the ACLU; misc. notes and clippings. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - STFU (Southern Tenant Farmers Union): chronology and ideology; Introduction; The Founding and Early History of the STFU, by H.L. Mitchell; Constitution of the Arkansas Tenant Farmers Union. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - STFU (continued): ideology - oral history with Gardner Jackson, typed and written notes intermingled. (Box 6, Folder 5,6,7)
  - STFU (continued): La Follette Committee - Farm Holiday Association Memoirs; interview with John Bosel, 11/4/61;interview with Richard Bosch, 11/4/61;notes. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - STFU (continued): movements; notes. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - STFU (continued): movements (continued) - 1975newsletter; xerox of pages from Man on the Move, by Nels Anderson; pages from Three Years of the AAA; misc. reference notes. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - STFU (continued) and other unions - The STFU and the CIO, by Mark Nelson; notes. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - STFU (continued): conclusions -Mob Attacks in Arkansas 4/13/75; The Southern Tenant Farmer Union, booklet of excerpts from interviews conducted by the Institute for Southern Studies. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - UFW - Chronology. 1973-76;conference at UFW headquarters; Cesar Chavez speaking at a gathering; interview with Philip Vera Cruz; interview with Chris and Dave Smith; Selected Bibliography, UFW, 1973-76;misc. flyers, articles. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - UFW - Chronology (continued): misc. notes. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - UFW - Convention: summary of the Third Constitutional Convention, UFW, AFL-CIO, 9/26-28/77;folders and materials for convention; UFW newsclippings (See Box 8, Folder 2). (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Union W.A.G.E. (Union Women's Alliance to Gain Equality): notes on Elizabeth Gurley Flynn and Mary Harris Jones from Women, Their Changing Roles; biographical sketch of Mary Harris Jones and Emma Goldman; clipping, Tribute to Women Union Organizers, 10/22/76;Union WAGE newsletters, 3-5/75;map to WAGE meeting. (See also correspondence from Anne Loftis to Lynn Donovan, 12/10/76;to Pat Palmer, 4/27/76;and to Jean Simpson, 4/30/75).(See Box 8, Folders 4, 5 for Union WAGE clippings) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Other Women's Labor Unions: syllabus for women's labor history: 19th and 20th century America; Matilda Lindsey and the NWTUL: Labor in the Southeast, by Josephine F. Pacheco. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Unions - Miscellaneous: Syndicalism - Law and Trials (concerning unions; written notes on The Silent Defenders, Courts and Capitalism in California, by Harvey Duff; To the Beasts, by Calif. General Defense Committee; The IWW's First Fifty Years (1905-1955)by Fred Thompson; The Wobblies by Patrick Renshaw; Go East, Young Man by William Douglass; notes also on Charlotte Anita Whitney, Supreme Court Reporter; misc. reference (see also Appendix, Box 8, Folder 11). (Box 6, Folder 18)
- U.S. GOVERNMENT INVOLVEMENTS WITH AGRICULTURE
  - AAA Background and Policy: pages (xerox) from Economic Resources and Policies in the South; reference notes. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - California Committee on Immigration and Housing - reference notes. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Farm Security Administration - reference notes. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - USDA-Policy and People: interviews, 1/53 - 10/66with Dean Albertson about Jesse Tapp and Rexford Tugwell; with Willa Bava about Cully Cobb. (Box 6, Folder 22)
- PUBLICATIONS
  - Catholic Worker newspaper: 1/72 - 6/74 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Catholic Worker newspaper: 7/74 - 5/75 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Catholic Worker newspaper: 6/75 - 12/76 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Catholic Worker newspaper: 1/77 - 5/78 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - El Malcriado (UFW, AFL - CIO newspaper): 1/66 - 1/74 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - El Malcriado (UFW, AFL - CIO newspaper): 2/74 - 10/74 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - El Malcriado (UFW, AFL - CIO newspaper): 11/74 - 1/75 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Land Worker magazine: 8/74 - 2/75 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Land Worker magazine: 3/75 - 6/75 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Land Worker magazine: 7/75 - 10/75 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - NACL pamphlets, 1977-78 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - National Farm Workers Ministry. NFWM newsletter, seven editions summer/75 to spring/78;NFWM to Action Mailing List, 5/30/75 and 3/23/77;NFWM bulletin for upcoming events (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - UFW: newsclippings, press releases (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Misc. clippings re Mexican and Cuban immigrants, other farm workers (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Misc. clippings, 9/76 - 6/77 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Misc. clippings, 7/77 - 4/78 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photostats of the Visalia Times-Delta, 10/9/33 - 11/21/33concerning farm workers' strike (Folder Oversized folder)
- SOURCES FOR FURTHER RESEARCH (Box 8, Folder 6-9)
  - Bibliography of some of the materials used in this collection and/or to be used for future research; written notes, xeroxes, etc.
- DOCUMENTS FOR APPENDIX
  - Collective Bargaining Agreement, 4/16/73;chart and tables; percent farm population in Calif. and U.S.; Mexican Nationals employed and unemployed (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Condition of Farm Workers and Small Farmers, six issues, yearly 1971-75;farm labor organizing bibliography; Outsiders in the System, by Friedland and Dorothy Nelkin; chart of official Calif. State Dept. of Employment, Division of Farm Labor Service; agricultural agreement between employers and Puerto Rican Agricultural workers; Appendix - Criminal syndicalism: A Prospectus for a History of Farm Labor Organizing (Box 8, Folder 11)